ADRIAN F. FERRAR

E: aferrar90@gmail.com W: https://aferrar.github.io/ P: 917-622-8525

Geospatial analyst and developer with a solid foundation in GIS, programming, and asset management. Experience solving geospatial problems, automating large dataset upkeep, producing insightful web maps, and collaborating with stakeholders on citywide initiatives.

EDUCATION

Hunter College: Geography Dept.

Master of Science in Geoinformatics

Graduated May 2018

The City College of New York: Earth & Atmospheric Science Dept.

Graduated May 2014

Bachelor of Science in Earth System Science, Minor in Economics

RELEVANT COURSEWORK

- Quantitative Methods in Geography
- ❖ Advanced GeoVisualization
- ❖ GeoComputation II
- ❖ GeoComputation I
- GeoWeb Services

- * Remote Sensing of Environment
- Urban Applications of GIS
- ❖ NYC Water Supply
- Database Modeling
- Advanced GIS

TECHNICAL KNOWLEDGE

Operating Systems: Windows, Linux

Development Environments: Visual Studio Code, Jupyter Lab/Notebook, Brackets, Emacs

Languages: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Python, R, SQL Databases: PostgreSQL, Microsoft SQL Server

Version Control: Git

APIs, Software and Libraries: Google Maps, ArcGIS Pro/Map/Catalog, ArcGIS Online, ArcGIS for Developers,

ENVI, GDAL/OGR, QGIS, Cessium, Leaflet, CartoDB, Tableau, Docker, Mapbox, GeoPandas, NumPy

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

NYC Department of City Planning

October 2018 – Present

GIS Specialist

120 Broadway. Manhattan, NY

Working under Enterprise Data Management division to assure timely and accurate maintenance of all geospatial data products through scripted automation. Unique understanding of inter-agency geo-data pipelines regarding NYC governance and public service utilization.

- Developed scripted pipelines for proper internal distribution of SDE sources, file-system layers and metadata associated with scheduled data set releases (LION, MapPLUTO, E-Designations, POPS, MIH, Building Footprints, LPC datasets, etc).
- Maintaining updates to The Guide to Planning Resources (internal web platform for sharing data resources across divisions) through combination of ArcGIS Hub, ArcGIS Online, and Github platform management.
- o Automated distribution of zoning and tax map data sets to FTP server.
- o Scripted assistance with CDBG eligible, PAS, and other analytical projects.
- Contributed to transition of MapPLUTO data set generation via automated PostGIS to ESRI conversion process using Python.
- o Completed select courses from agency provided Land Use Academy training for improved understanding of related topics in zoning, site selection, data resources, and more.

NYC Department of Transportation

January 2017 – June 2018

College Aide

55 Water Street. Manhattan, NY

While working under Asset Management division, tasked with maintaining various geodatabases with python scripts to automate regularly modifying tasks in large datasets. Also maintained various MS Access DBs.

- Increased office workflow efficiency by developing automated scripts for updating File Geodatabases and SDE server repository records for street assets.
- Contributed to the development of a citywide predictive Street Deterioration Model using R, SQL, and Python.
- o Managed the analysis of historical commitments for all DOT bridge, street, and facility assets seeking to spatialize and evaluate funding patterns within various political boundaries.
- Led the collection and digitization of all NYC street ownership records. Worked in collaboration with Department of City Planning and the respective City Borough President's Topography Departments. Developed QA process for evaluating digitization metrics.

New York Restoration Project

May 2016 - December 2016

AmeriCorps Environmental Steward 255 Liberty Avenue. Brooklyn, NY

Environmental steward involved in fostering community environment and maintaining garden asset responsibilities in areas of Brownsville, Brooklyn.

 Participated in and planned outreach events, volunteer field projects, and provided technical support and training to community gardeners.

Atlas Environmental Lab

August 2015 - December 2015

Environmental Laboratory Analyst 255 W. 36th St. New York, NY

Laboratory researcher involved with examination of potential asbestos containing materials (ACMs).

 Analyzed bulk and airborne filter samples using stereo, phase-contrast, and polarized-light microscopy and prepared paint, soil, dust wipe, and composited wipe samples for environmental lead analysis via AAS.

Telepathy

September 2014 - August 2015

Programming Intern 68 Jay St. Brooklyn, NY

Personal assistant to independent programmer. Aided in development of mobile applications.

o Tested, debugged, and modified small-scale iOS and Android applications.

The City College of New York

January 2013 - May 2014

Undergraduate Research Assistant

160 Convent Avenue New York, NY 10031

Undergraduate researcher tasked with the design and implementation of experiments studying interactions between virus, bacteria, and clay particulates.

 Examined biological material interaction and supervised laboratory protocols for proper equipment maintenance and biohazard removal.

CERTIFICATIONS

Penn State University - Graduate certification in Sustainability, Management and Policy

REFERENCES

References Available Upon Request